Temple, Nelson, Lloyd, Vassall, and Borland family papers (bMS Am 1250): Guide.
Temple, Nelson, Lloyd, Vassall, and Borland family papers,
1611-1862 (inclusive),1700-1831 (bulk).
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1250
9 boxes (4.5 linear ft.)
Papers of U.S. senator James Lloyd and others related to the Temple, Melson, Lloys, Vassall, and Borland families.
*51M-225.
Gift of Mrs. G. L. Batchelder Jr.,; Gordon Abbott, and Mrs. Francis B. Lothrop; received: 1951.
James Lloyd (1728-1810) was an obstetrician and surgeon in Boston, Mass.; James Lloyd (1769-1831) was a U.S. senator from Massachusetts from 1808 to 1814.
Organized into the following series:
I. Addenda to the Temple-Nelson papers
II. Legal documents
III. Vassall correspondence
IV. Correspondence of Henry and Dr. James Lloyd
V. Correspondence of Senator James Lloyd
VI. Letters from Senator Lloyd
VII. Borland correspondence
VIII. Membership diplomas
IX. Genealogical data
X. Newspaper clippings
XI. Pictures
XII. Deeds
Contains correspondence, legal documents, and other family papers of the related Temple, Nelson, Lloyd, Vassall, and Borland families of Massachusetts, Nova Scotia, and Jamaica, West Indies.Most of the collection consists of the correspondence of Senator James Lloyd with national figures, such as President John Adams, Marquis de Lafayette and Andrew Jackson, other political associates, and family members and friends. The correspondence of his father and grandfather, James and Henry Lloyd, concerns personal business and medical matters, mostly with family members. The letters to William Vassall pertain to his personal and business affairs. Collection also contains legal documents, genealogical data, clippings, membership diplomas, account books, and photographs. The legal documents are land claims, deeds, wills, contracts, and writs. Additional documents of the Temple and Nelson families are included in the collection.
- I. Addenda to the Temple-Nelson papers
  - Parkhurst, Robert. Lease of Sir Thomas Temple's portion of Nova Scotia. [N.p.] 3 Oct 1656., (1); 1s.(2p.)
    on vellum. Signed by Robert Parkhurst.
  - Nelson, Robert, d. 1698. A.L.s. to [Thomas] Nelson; St. Mar. 1 May 1670., (2); 1s.(1p.)
    Annotated by John Nelson (1654-1734)
  - Nelson, Paschal, d. 1760. Memorial [supporting his claim to Nova Scotia] MS. (unidentified hand); [n.p., ca. 1750], (3); 3s.(8p.)
  - Nelson, Paschal, d. 1760. Extract from a letter written by Mr. John Nelson to Monsr. De Vaudreule... A.MS.s.; [n.p., ca. 1750], (4); 1s.(1p.)
    Document prepared by Nelson in support of his claim.
  - [Nelson, Paschal, d. 1760.] A.L.(unsigned; incomplete) to [ ]; London, 4 Sep 1754., (5); 1s.(4p.)
  - Temple, Sir Thomas, bart., 1614-1674. Last will and testament. MS.(contemporary copy); Boston, 14 Oct 1611., (6); 1s.(2p.)
- II. Legal documents
  - Survey by Jonathan Danforth of a farm in Billerica. Billerica, 18 May 1682., (7); 1s.(2p.)
    Contemporary copy.
  - Last will and testament of James Lloyd. Boston, 10 Apr 1684., (8); 1s.(4p.)
    19th century certified copy, signed by John Heard.
  - Deed to Leonard Vassall of land in Jamaica by Anna Vassall. Jamaica, 30 Dec 1699., (9); 1s.(4p.)
    18th century copy of the original.
  - Deed by Joseph Bridgham to John Borland of land in Boston. Boston, 9 Apr 1700., (10); 1s.(2p.)
    on vellum. Signed by Joseph Bridgham; witnessed and attested by Eliezer Moody, Jeremiah Richards, John Walley, Addington Davenport.
  - Deed by Zacheriah Trescott and Mary Trescott to Nicholas Boone of property on Cornhill. Boston, 22 Apr 1715., (11); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by Zacheriah and Mary Trescott; witnessed and attested by John Allen, James Cummings, Samuel Lynde, John Ballantine.
  - Last will and testament of Anna Vassall. Jamaica, 19 Jun 1717., (12); 2s.(8p.)
    Late 18th century copy.
  - Last will and testament of Anna Vassall. Jamaica, 20 Feb 1719., (13); 1s.(2p.)
    Contemporary copy of the original.
  - Last will and testament of William Vassall. Jamaica, 3 Aug 1720., (14); 4s.(6p.)
    Contemporary MS. copy of the original.
  - Deed by Cyprian Southack to John Jekyll of land on Tremont Street, Boston. Boston, 19 Jan 1724., (15); 1s.(2p.)
    on vellum. Signed by Cyprian Southack and Elizabeth Southack,; Samuel Checkley,; John Ballantine,; Thomas Lewis,; Joseph Marion.
  - Survey of lands patented by John Vassall. Jamaica, 26 Aug 1734. Contemporary copy of plot and description made by William Dunbar and Alexander Skeen., (16)
  - Deed of gilt by Timothy Lindall to Francis Borland and Jane Borland of property in Taunton. Boston, 25 Jul 1736., (17); 1s.(3p.)
    Signed by Timothy Lindall; witnessed and attested by Benjamin Eliot, Luke Vardy, Daniel Henchman, Samuel Howland.
  - Last will and testament of Leonard Vassall. Boston, 25 Sep 1756., (18); 8f. (13p.)
    Signed by Leonard Vassall; witnesses Moses Eayres, Sarah Dolliver, John Breilsford, Josiah Crosboy.
  - Last will and testament of Leonard Vassall. Boston, 10 Jun 1737., (19); 10f.(13p.)
    Certified copy, attested by John Boydell and Jonathan Belcher. With 3 additional copies.
  - Writ by Prerogative court of Canterbury for Thomas Hitchins to administer the estate of his deceased wife Anne. Canterbury, 29 Aug 1739., (20); 1s.(1p.)
    on vellum. Signed by William Legard,; Peter St. Eloy, and Henry Stevens.
  - Writ by Prerogative court of Canterbury concerning administration by Thomas Hitchins of estate of his late wife Anne. Canterbury, 10 Sep 1739., (21); 1s.(1p.)
  - Deed to John Comrin of real estate on Cornhill by heirs of Nicholas Boone. Boston, 3 Dec. 1742., (22); 2s.(4p.)
    Signed by Nicholas Boone and Mary Boone,; Paul Farmer and Hannah Farmer,; Elizabeth Boone and Mary Boone,; William Dawes and Lydia Dawes; witnessed and attested by Timothy Green, William Morton, Thomas Hubbard, Ezekiel Goldthwait.
  - Agreement of Henry Vassall to cede to his brother, William, his rights in the Jamaica estate of their father Leonard Vassall. Boston, 28 Dec 1742., (23); 1s.(1p.)
    on vellum. Signed by Henry Vassall; witnesses Richard Bill, John Connelly, John Sutcliff, Joshua Henshaw Jr.; attested by Samuel Sewall, G. Willard, Sir William Shirley.
  - Last will and testament of John Vassall. Cambridge, 27 Nov 1747., (24); 4f.(6p.)
    Certified copy, attested by Sir William Shirley and J. Willard.
  - An [account] of what is this day deliver'd to Mr John Borland his lady Anna Borland the heiress to Leonard Vassall deceas'd... Boston, 13 Mar 1749/50., (25); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by Samuel Sewall.
  - Power of attorney of William Vassall to George Ruggles and George Mackay. Jamaica, 21 Mar 1750. Printed form filled out in MS. Unsigned., (26)
  - Affidavit of Ebenezer Pomroy regarding certain land at Stockbridge. Northampton, 17 Mar 1752., (27); 1s.(2p.)
    Contemporary copy of original.
  - Survey by Robert Fletcher Jr. of land belonging to Francis Borland near Peterboro, N. H. [N.p.] 10 Oct 1754., (28); 1s.(2p.)
  - 1754-1760. 2 contracts for paw rental and 1 receipt for purchase of tomb in Kings Chapel by William Vassall. Boston, 6 Dec 1754,24 Jul 1759,20 Oct 1760., (29); 3s.(5p.)
    in wrapper. Among the signatories are William Vassall,; Charles Apthorp,; Stephen Apthorp,; George Gradock,; William Hutchinson,; John Gibbins,; Silvester Gardiner,; Thomas Hawden,; Henry Caner,; Peter Roberts Jr. The pew rentals are printed forms filled out in MS.
  - Invoice of sundrys ship'd by Sam Vaughan on board the Three Friends... London, 28 May 1756., (30); 1s.(1p.)
    Signed by Sam Vaughan.
  - Last will and testament of Timothy Lindall. Salem, 7 Jul 1760., (31); 4f.(8p.)
    Certified copy signed by Daniel Noyes. With another certified copy signed by Daniel Appleton. 6f.(9p.)
  - Last will and testament of Henry Lloyd. Boston, 3 Mar 1763., (32); 2s.(3p.)
  - Last will and testament of Francis Borland. Boston, 7 Mar 1763., (33); 1s.(4p.)
    Certified copy signed by John Cotton. With another copy in the hand of Mrs. Gordon Abbott.
  - Deed of property on Cornhill to Jonathan Mason by Sarah Comrin. Boston, 31 Oct 1763., (34); 1s.(4p.)
    Signed by Sarah Comrin; witnessed and attested by John Greenleaf, William Story, Ezekiel Goldthwait.
  - Deed of release of farm at Quenns village to James Lloyd by Henry Lloyd,; John Lloyd, and Joseph Lloyd. [N.p.] 22 Jun 1764., (35); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by Henry, John, and Joseph Lloyd; witnessed and attested by Nathaniel Hubbard, William Smith, Samuel Willis, Henry Smith, Paschal Nelson Smith, William Eutchinson, William Brattle.
  - Receipts covering settlement of estate of Francis Lindall Borland. Boston, 15-25 Oct 1765., (36); 3s.(5p.)
  - Power of attorney by Sarah Comrin and Sarah Lloyd and James Lloyd to John Richie. [Boston] 29 Mar 1766., (37); 1s.(3p.)
    Signed by Sarah Comrin, Sarah Lloyd, James Lloyd; witnesses Gilbert Deblois and Thomas Hutchinson Jr.
  - Note of James Barrick to John Borland. Boston, 4 May 1769., (38); 1s.(2p.)
    Printed form filled out in MS. Signed by James Barrick; witnesses William Lanyon, Samuel Wallis.
  - Note of Samuel Quincy to John Borland. Boston, 2 Apr 1711., (39); 1s.(2p.)
    Printed form filled out in MS. Signed by Samuel Quincy; witnesses George Spooner, Sarah Empson.
  - Commission of James Lloyd as Justice of the Peace. Boston, 12 Aug1772., (40); 1s.(2p.)
    in wrapper. Printed form filled out in MS. Signed by Thomas Hutchinson.
  - Note of Ephraim Heald to John Borland. Boston, 1 Jan 1774., (41); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by Ephraim Heald; witnesses Isaac Stearns, William Stearns, Sarah Nash.
  - Last will and testament of John Borland. Boston, 3 Jun 1775., (42); 1s.(2p.)
    Certified copy signed by John Cotton.
  - Papers concerning James Llayd's loyalty to the British crown. Boston, 1777 - 1778., (43); 14 pieces.
    Affidavits, resolutions, and other documents concerning Lloyd's refusal to take oath of allegiance to the United States.
  - Contract between Col. George Clark and Francis Green for cutting firewood on Lloyds Neck. New York, 30 Nov 1779., (44); 1s.(4p.)
  - Power of attorney by William Vassall to James Lloyd and Oliver Smith. [London] 31 Mar 1788., (45); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by William Vassal; witnesses Shirley Erving and William Randall.
  - Certified copy of baptismal record of William Vassall, son of John and Elizabeth Vassall, Jamaica, June 1720. Jamaica, 10 May - 4 Jun 1784., (46); 6f.(4p.)
    with seal of Jamaica. Attested by Archibald Campbell, William Dunlop, Thomas Warren, Humphrey Colquhoun, and Thomas S. Salmon.
  - Receipt of John Borland for payment of bequest of Timothy Lindall. Boston, 4 Oct 1784., (47); 1s.(3p.)
  - Agreement between James Sullivan and Leonard Vassall Borland regarding estate of John Borland. Boston, 30 Nov 1784., (48); 1s.(2p.)
  - Receipt of Francis Borland for payment of bequest by Timothy Lindall. Boston, 27 Dec 1784., (49); 1s.(2p.)
  - Agreement between William Vassall and attorneys for Mary Hayley regarding house and land in Boston. London, 26 Jul 1786., (50); 4f.(6p.); Signed by William Vassall,; Francis Rotch,; Alexander Sprague Jr.; witnessed and attestes by John Evans, J. H. Appleton, James Scott, Samuel Spragg, R. Wilson, Thomas Sainsbury.
  - Deed to Leonard Vassall Borland of farm in Newton by Phinehas Bond. Boston, 3 Oct 1786., (51); 1s.(1p.)
    on vellum. Signed by Phinehas Bond and Thankfull Bond; witnesses Samuel and Patty Saunders Barrett, Thomas Allen, Abel Johnson.
  - Contracts between John Erving Jr.,; George Lush, and James Lloyd regarding sale of property owned by John Erving Sr. Boston, 3 Jan 1787., (52); 1s.(4p.)
    Signed by John Erving and George Lush; witness Harrison Gray Otis.
  - Deed of property owned by John Erving Sr., made by Richard Cranch,; Samuel Henshaw and Samuel Barrett as a committee to James Lloyd. Boston, 4 Jan 1787., (53); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by Richard Cranch,; Samuel Henshaw,; Samuel Barrett; witnessed and attested by Samuel Janes, [ ] Farrington, Cotton Tufts, E. Foster, Israel Keith, Nathaniel Greenleaf.
  - Report of appraisers regarding property on Kilby Street. Boston, 14 Jan 1787., (54); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by Samuel Dyer,; Samuel Ruggles,; Thomas Clement.
  - Quit claim deed of John Srving (through John Erving Jr.) to James Lloyd of property on Kilby Street. Boston, 21 Mar 1787., (55); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by John Erving Jr.; witnessed and attested by Samuel Barrett, E. Sohier.
  - Bill from Theodore Deshon to James Lloyd for services as hairdresser. [Boston] 23 Mar 1787., (56); 1s.(4p.)
  - Power of attorney by William Vassall to James Lloyd and John Lowell. [London] 26 Feb 1790., (57); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by William Vassall; witnesses Harrison Gray Jr. and James Scott.
  - Power of attorney by William Vassall to James Lloyd and John Lowell. [London] 26 Feb 1790., (58); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by William Vassall; witnesses Russell Hubbard and W. Greenland.
  - Power of attorney by William Vassall to James Lloyd. [London] 26 Feb 1790., (59); 1s.(3p.)
  - Power of attorney by William Vassall to James Lloyd. [London] 26 Feb 1790., (60); 1s.(3p.)
  - A list of land belonging to Wm. Vassall on Kennebeck river. [London] 22 Jul 1794., (61); 1s.(2p.)
    Evidently prepared for the use of Vassall's attorney, James Lloyd.
  - Deed to Leonard Vassall Borland of property inherited from John Borland by Francis Borland. Boston, 23 Dec 1794., (62); 1s.(4p.)
    Signed by Francis Borland, witnesses Ezekiel Price, Robert Lash Jr.
  - Partnership agreement of Henry Jackson Oliver,; John Borland, and Samuel Leonard Abbot. Boston, 1 Jan 1814., (63); 4f.(7p.)
    Signed by Henry J. Oliver,; John Borland,; Samuel L. Abbot; witnesses James Lloyd, Samuel Abbot.
  - Commission of James Lloyd as Justice of the Peace. Boston, 18 Jan 1819., (64); 1s.(2p.)
    Printed form filled out in MS. Signed by John Brooks and Alden Bradford.
  - Partnership agreement of Henry Jackson Oliver,; John Borland, and Samuel Leonard Abbot. Boston, 1 Jan 1821., (65); 4f.(8p.)
    Signed by Henry J. Oliver,; John Borland,; Samuel L. Abbot; witnessed by Samuel Abbot, William S. Cruft.
  - Printed announcement of dissolution of Oliver,; Borland, and Abbot, and formation of Borland and Abbot. Boston, 1 Jan 1825., (66); 1s.(2p.)
    Signed by John Borland and Samuel L. Abbot.
  - Documents connected with probating the will of Sen. James Lloyd. Boston, 4 Jun 1831., (67); 4s.(3p.)
    Signed by Levi Lincoln,; Edward D. Bangs,; Joseph Hall,; John Heard.
- III. Vassall correspondence
  - Conybeare, John, bp. of Bristol, 1692-1755. A.L.s. (Jn. Bristol) to [William] Vassall; London, 29 Jun 1750., (68); 1s.(4p.)
  - Fowle, John. A.L.s. to William Vassall; Boston, Mar 1741., (69); 1s.(3p.)
- Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790. 2 A.L.s. to William Vassall, as follows:
  - Philadelphia, 29 May 1746., (70); 1s.(3p.)
    repaired.
  - Same, 19 Jun 1746., (71); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnson, Samuel. A.L.s. to [William] Vassall; Stratford, 5 Apr 1752., (72); 1s.(2p.)
- Lloyd, James, 1728-1810. 4 A.L.s.(copies) to William Vassall, as follows:
  - Boston, 26 Aug 1781., (73); 1s.(3p.)
  - [Same] 3 Feb 1788., (74); 1s.(1p.)
    fragment only.
  - Same, 21 Nov 1788., (75); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 7 Nov 1797., (76); 1s.(1p.)
- Mackay, Hugh. 2 A.L.s. to William Vassall, as follows:
  - Halifax, 28 Jan 1757., (77); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 25 May 1757., (78); 1s.(3p.)
- Otis, James, 1725-1783. 3 A.L.s. to William Vassall, as follows:
  - Boston, 1 Sep 1753., (79); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 28 Sep 1753., (80); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 22 Oct 1753., (81); 1s.(3p.)
- Quincy, Edmund, 1703-1788. A.L.s. to William Vassall; Braintree, 4 Sep 1755., (82); 1s.(3p.)
- Sewall, Samuel. A.L.s. to William Vassall; Boston, 13 Jul 1737., (83); 1s.(3p.)
- Stedman, Leonard. 2 A.L.s. to William Vassall, as follows:
  - Jamaica, 7 Jun 1760., (84); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 17 Jun 1760., (85); 1s.(2p.)
- Vassall, Ann. A.L.s. to Ann Vassall Simpson; Cheltenham, 16 Apr 1824., (86); 1s.(4p.)
- Vassall, Florentius, d. 1778. A.L.s. to William Vassall; London, 31 May 1774., (87); 1s.(2p.)
- Vassall, Leonard. Directions for boiling of sugar... A.MS.s.; [Jamaica, 17--?], (88); 8f.(9p.)
- Vassall, Lewis, b. 1741. A.L.s. to William Vassall; Jamaica, 7 Oct 1766., (89); 1s.(4p.)
- Vassall, William, 1715-1800. 2 A.L.s.(copies) to James Bowdoin, as follows:
  - Clapham Common, 19 Aug 1785., (90); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 26 Jul 1786., (91); 1s.(2p.)
- Vassall, William, 1715-1800. Account book. [V.p.] 1747-1761. 1v. Original vellum binding., (92)
- Vassall, William, 1753-1843. 4 A.L.s. to William Vassall Sr., as follows:
  - Edinburgh, 20 Feb 1773., (93); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 17 Mar 1773., (94); 1s.(4p.)
  - London, 4 Jan 1774., (95); 1s.(4p.)
  - Oxford, 13 Jul 1774., (96); 1s.(4p.)
- IV. Correspondence of Henry and Dr. James Lloyd
  - Dibble, E. A.L.s. to [James] Lloyd; Queens village, 19 Mar 1763., (97); 1s.(3p.)
    On the death of Henry Lloyd.
  - Faneuil, Mary. A.L.s. to [Sarah (Comrin)] Lloyd; Cambridge, 30 Apr 1763., (98); 1s.(2p.)
  - Faneuil, Mary. A.L.s. to [James] Lloyd; Cambridge, 14 Jun 1775., (99); 1s.(2p.)
  - Fraser, Simon. MS.L.s. to John Comrin; Gibraltar, 26 Jan 1757., (100); 1s.(2p.)
  - Gill, Sarah (Prince) 1728-1774. A.L.s. to [Sarah (Comrin)] Lloyd; 23 Feb 1760., (101); 1s.(4p.)
  - Humphreys, Henry. A.L.s. to [James Lloyd]; London, 14 Aug 1789., (102); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lloyd, Gershom. MS.L.(copy) to Henry Lloyd; [Jamaica] 7 Aug 1747., (103); 1s.(2p.)
  - Lloyd, Henry, d. 1763. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Queens village, 23 Aug 1754., (104); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 12 Apr 1755., (105); 1s.(2p.)
  - Lloyd, Henry, d. 1795. 10 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Halifax, 23 Sep 1782., (106); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 30 May 1783., (107); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 14 Jul 1783., (108); 1s.(4p.)
    - New York, 15 Nov 1783., (109); 1s.(3p.)
    - Halifax, 19 Feb 1784., (110); 2s.(6p.)
    - London, 26 Feb 1788., (111); 1s.(2p.)
      defective.
    - Same, 40ct - 3 Nov 1788., (112); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 18-23 Dec 1793., (113); 2s.(8p.)
    - Same, 23 Dec 1793., (114); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 23 Mar 1795., (115); 1s.(4p.)
  - Lloyd, Henry, Jr. 3 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Hartford, 30 Oct 1780., (116); 1s.(3p.)
    - Queens village, 8 Dec 1788., (117); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 1 May 1795., (118); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lloyd, James, 1728-1810. 17 A.L.s. to Henry Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 16 Aug 1745., (119); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 3 Oct 1745., (120); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 13 Apr 1746., (121); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 23 Jul 1748., (122); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 7 Apr 1749., (123); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 24 May 1749., (124); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 25 Sep 1749., (125); 1s.(2p.)
    - London, 4 Mar 1750/1., (126); 2s.(4p.)
    - Same, 4 Dec 1751., (127); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 11 Mar 1752., (128); 1s.(2p.)
    - Boston, 22 May 1752., (129); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 12 Aug 1752., (130); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 18 Jul 1757., (131); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 24 Oct 1757., (132); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 25 May 1761., (133); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 9 Dec 1762., (134); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 17 Feb 1763., (135); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lloyd, James, 1728-1810. A.L.s. (draft) to Gilbert Deblois; Boston, 29 Mar 1766., (136); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lloyd, James, 1728-1810. A.L.s. (draft) to [ ] Phipps; Boston, 23 Sep 1786., (137); 1s.(2p.)
  - Lloyd, James, 1769-1831. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 15 Feb 1810., (138); 1s.(4p.)
  - Lloyd, John, b. 1711. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Stamford, 10 Jul 1766., (139); 1s.(3p.)
  - Lloyd, William. A.L.s. to Henry Lloyd; [Jamaica] 26 Jan 1748., (140); 1s.(3p.)
    Contains epitaph on Oershom Lloyd.
  - Mallet, J. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 18 Nov 1775., (141); 1s.(2p.)
  - Murray, John. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Fredericton, 17 Jul 1787., (142); 1s.(2p.)
    With Lloyd's disallowed claim against Murray's absentee estate. 1s.(2p.)
  - Prescott, Jonathan. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Halifax, 29 May 1759., (143); 1s.(2p.)
  - Prevost, Augustine. 2 A.L.s. to [James Lloyd], as follows:
    - Louisbourg, 20 Jun 1758., (144); 1s.(3p.)
    - [N.p., 10 Jul 1758], (145); 1s.(2p.)
  - Seabury, Samuel, bp., 1729-1796. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; New London, 22 Nov 1786., (146); 1s.(2p.)
  - Temple, Sir John. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; New York, 29 Dec 1788., (147); 1s.(4p.)
  - Vassall, William, 1715-1800. 11 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Nantucket, 3 Jun 1775., (148); 1s.(2p.)
    - Clapham Common, 14 Aug 1783., (149); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, [ ] Sep 1783., (150); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 23 Mar 1784., (151); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 23 Jul - 1 Sep 1784., (152); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 13 Mar 1787., (153); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 3 Mar 1790., (154); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 30 Oct - 5 Nov 1794., (155); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 24 - 27 Mar 1795., (156); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 7 Aug 1797., (157); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.], (158); 1s.(2p.)
  - Warner, Joseph. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; London, 4 Jul 1763., (159); 1s.(3p.)
- V. Correspondence of Senator James Lloyd
  - Adams, John, pres. U. S., 1735-1826. 19 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Quincy, 28 Jan 1815., (160); 3s.(9p.)
    - Same, 6 Feb 1815., (161); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 11 Feb 1815., (162); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 14 Feb 1815., (163); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 17 Feb 1815., (164); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 21 Feb 1815., (165); 3s.(7p.)
    - Same, 28 Feb 1815., (166); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 6 Mar 1815., (167); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 9 Mar 1815., (168); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 12 Mar 1815., (169); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 26 Mar 1815., (170); 3s.(9p.)
    - Same, 27 Mar 1815., (171); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 29 Mar 1815., (172); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 30 Mar 1815., (173); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 31 Mar 1815., (174); 2s.(5p.)
    - Same, 5 Apr 1815., (175); 2s.(6p.)
    - Same, 22 Apr 1815., (176); 2s.(4p.)
    - Same, 24 Apr 1815., (177); 4s.(13p.)
    - Same, 8 Aug 1815., (178); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, MS.L. (copy) from William Stephens Smith to John Adams; New York, 11 Apr 1815., (179); 1s.(4p.)
  - Adams, John Quincy, pres. U. S., 1767-1848. 5 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Washington, 15 Jul 1822., (180); 2s.(3p.)
    - Same, 1 Oct 1822., (181); 2s.(5p.)
    - Boston, 8 Oct 1825., (182); 1s.(2p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.] Statement on John Randolph., (183); 1s.(1p.)
    - [N.p., n.d.] MS.L.s., fragment only., (184)
  - Austin, Daniel. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; [Portsmouth, 25 Oct 1813], (185); 1s.(3p.)
    includes draft of Lloyd's reply.
  - Bainbridge, William, 1774-1833. 2 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Charlestown, Mass., 22 Dec 1823., (196); 1s.(2p.)
    - Norfolk, Va., 1 Feb 1824., (187); 1s.(3p.)
  - Bank of the United States, 1816-1836. MS.L.s. (by the Directors) to James Lloyd; Boston, 18 Sep 1816., (188); 1s.(2p.)
  - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Washington, 12 Jan 1827., (189); 1s.(4p.)
  - Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844. 3 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Philadelphia, 18 Jun 1824., (190); 1s.(2p.)
    - [Same] 5 Nov 1825., (191); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 28 Aug 1828., (192); 1s.(1p.)
  - Borland, Francis. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Somerset, 1 Mar 1822., (193); 1s.(4p.)
  - Borland, James Lloyd. A.L.s. to James Lloyd; Boston, 9 Dec 1829., (194); 1s.(4p.)
  - Borland, John. 9 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Boston, 26 Apr 1812., (195); 1s.(2p.)
    - Alexandria, 23 Feb 1821., (196); 1s.(4p.)
    - Richmond, 2 Mar 1821., (197); 1s.(4p.)
    - Boston, 8 Apr 1825., (198); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 13 Dec 1825., (199); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 29 Dec 1825., (200); 1s.(2p.)
    - Same, 6 Jan 1826., (201); 1s.(3p.)
    - Same, 24 May 1829., (202); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 12 Oct 1829., (203); 1s.(4p.)
  - Borland, Samuel. 5 A.L.s. to James Lloyd, as follows:
    - Kinderhook, 16 May 1813., (204); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 25 May 1813., (205); 1s.(4p.)
    - Hudson, 27 Mar 1822., (206); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 22 Jul 1822., (207); 1s.(4p.)
    - Same, 31 Oct 1823., (208); 1s.(4p.)